The most accurate quote promoting health insurance policies these days
is that you're just a
single hospitalization away from
falling below the poverty line. This is true to a large extent.
A single hospitalization
can bring you below the poverty line. But did you know
that even your health insurance policy ca
n't take you below the poverty line? If
you haven't purchased the best health insurance policy
from the best health insurance company,
you'll now be asking
which is the best health insurance policy and
which is the best health insurance company. When you
purchase a health insurance policy,
what do you check? The claim
settlement ratio. You'll check the in-currence claim
ratio. You'll check the network hospitals. The
most you'll check is
its solvency ratio.
If you talk about the claim settlement ratio, it's
manipulated at 99. On every website
you check, the
claim settlement ratio is 99%, or 100%. But
at 99, it's manipulated. There's
even an insurance company whose
claim settlement ratio is available to you online.  It seems 100% that
15 to 20 claims have come to me this month and
they have been rejected, then
how did the claim settlement ratio become 100%? Now the
question arises that
how to choose the best health insurance policy. The
only objective of comparison is the
best product, best services and
economic price, but there is no guarantee that
you will get the best product and best services at an economic price
and it is
very difficult, but whenever you
purchase a health insurance policy, first of all
check what is the brand image of that company
because whenever you check the brand image
and purchase an insurance company with a good brand image, then
that
insurance company will not reject your claim unnecessarily.
Whenever that insurance company rejects your claim, there will be
some authentic reasons behind it.
In today's video, I have brought before you a
comparison of two health insurance plans and these two health insurance
plans are the health insurance plans which are the most
sold and most
popular today and Revolution Health
Insurance Plan  Yes, I'm going to talk about a
comparison of IC Lombard's Elevate plan with ADAC R Go's Optima Secure.
If we talk about IC Lombard's
Elevate plan, it was launched in July 2024. The
features of this plan are
not yet available in any other health insurance plan. These are
absolutely unique features.
If I talk about ADAC R Go, the Optima
Secure plan was launched in 2021.
It is a fully loaded health insurance
plan that guarantees 100% claim.
Fundamental:
IC R and hdfcfund.com
[Music]
Also, if you're visiting the insurance service for the first time,
subscribe to the insurance service now and press the bell icon
so you
get notifications of all my videos.
If you want to purchase your insurance through the insurance service,
you can also call us on the number given on the screen. So, let me
start
with IC Lombard's Elevate plan. The
Elevate plan has been designed in such a way
that  Everything in this policy is
unlimited. Whatever you purchase,
you will get it unlimited. There are many ads
in this policy and there are many
inbuilt features as well. First of all, I will talk about
unlimited time off. Take a policy of ₹ lakh, ₹ lakh, ₹ 20 lakh, 1 crore, 2 crore policy but ICC Lord has said in this policy that here you
can take the option of unlimited time off. Unlimited
time off means that
whatever expenses you incur by going to the hospital, the insurance company will bear it. Whatever expenses
you incur in pre and post, the
insurance company will bear it.
Whatever expenses you incur in day care, AYUSH, the
This is unlimited time off. This is the second time it has
come. Before this, another insurance
company has it but it
is not that popular but this is fundamentally strong
company with
unlimited time off. If you
add unlimited time off, then you
can take unlimited claim once in your life, that is,
if you have taken unlimited time off.  You have
not taken the loan option. You have taken a time shot of 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh.
You can take unlimited claim once in your life
and you will decide when to take that unlimited claim.
Many times it happens
that we have to undergo a transplant in life, we suffer from a
major disease, God forbid, we suffer from
serious diseases like cancer, then
unlimited claim is used there. So, by
taking the benefit of unlimited claim here,
you will get it with an infinite minimum. You
can add it to a policy ranging from 10 lakh to 2 crore rupees. Power
booster means that every year your time shot will
increase 100% and there will be an increase of N number of times, that is, it will
increase till life time. You have purchased a policy of ₹ 1 lakh today
and you have taken the add-on power
booster, then your ₹ 1 lakh will keep
increasing till life time, that is,
after 10 years, that policy will be worth 1 crore.
After 12 years it will become Rs 2 crore and after 30 years it will become Rs 3 crore
and you will get the power booster
even if there is a claim and even if there is no claim.
Also let's talk about Jump
Start. Jump Start is an add-on which
is already available in many companies
but Jump Start is an add-on where if
you have any pre-
registered
disease then you
can take its cover from 311 days by adding Jump Start.
You will have to pay a little additional premium in Jump Start.
Now let's talk about the
inflicting
reset. Unlimited reston will be for the same person, same illness
but for the same person, same
illness, you will have to wait for 40 days in the second claim
i.e. if a
claim has come today for X disease, to
take a claim again for X disease to the same person,
you will have to wait for 40 days in the restomination.
Maternity cover will be an add-on in this. 10 per cent of
the basic time apart, its maximum limit will be Rs 1 lakh,
so maternity is added on in this.
If you need maternity cover,
you can take it by adding it. Along with this,
you can take durable equipment cover
which will be an add-on cover.
What are durable equipment like, you have a
wheelchair, couches and
many other durable equipment
which are very costly, you
can add it on to it. So, let me talk about
ADA Sir C's Optima Secure, there
is Secure Benefit, buy one get one free. If you
take a policy of ₹1 lakh, then
you will get cover of ₹40 lakh from day one. If you take a policy of ₹1 lakh,
then you will get cover of ₹1 lakh from day one.
Protect Benefit,
you will get in-build consumer cover in Protect Benefit.
There,
in your Elevate plan in ICICI Lombard, you will have to take an add-on
for consumer cover, but
in ADFC Ergo, you are going to get in-build Plus Benefit.
In Plus Benefit,
your insurance will increase by 50% every time.  Up
to a maximum of 100% per year and it will be there even if there is a claim
and even if there is no claim. If you are
taking a policy of 20 lakhs, then you will get a cover of 40 lakhs
from day one because of the secure benefit,
but next year ₹10 lakhs will be
added as plus benefit and the
next year also you will get ₹10 lakhs plus benefit
added. They have the option of Optima Super Secure.
If you
pay a combined premium for 3 years and
add the option of Optima Super Secure, then
you will get three times coverage from day one, that is, 10 lakhs
is free with 10 lakhs.
There you will get 20 lakhs free with 10 lakhs.
So these are the special
features of both these plans. Now let
us talk about the basic features. The first thing that
comes in the basic feature is the time skip option. In the
ICC Lombard Elevate plan, the
time shot will start from ₹1 lakh and will end at unlimited.
Similarly,
in ADAC Rugo Optima Secure also  It will start from Rs 5 lakh,
but options up to Rs 3 crore will be
available to them. If we talk about the entry age, then the
minimum will be 18 years in both the
plans, but there is no limit on the maximum entry
age in both the plans. A
person of any age
can opt for this plan. The policy tenure is 1 year, 2 years,
3 years, 2 years and 3 years. By paying a premium of 2 years and 3 years, you can get a
discount on the premium
in both the policies, but by opting for Optima Super Secure,
you can get an additional term cover.
If you pay a premium of 3 years and
take Optima Super Secure, then
your secure benefit will be doubled, that is, if
you opt for a policy of ₹ 1 lakh, then you will get a
cover of 60 lakh from day one.
Talking about variants, there are no variants in Lombard's Elevate plan,
but with
Global and Global Plus in ADFC Ergo's Optima Secure plan,
you
can get treatment even outside India, and
you will not get this facility in ICC Lombard's Elevate
plan. Family Size
IC Lombard Elevate Plan  Two adults and three kids,
but in SDFC R or Optima Secure,
you can take the option of two adults and four kids.
Talking about room rent, it is a very
important feature
for any insurance company because room rent
is that demon, that monster which makes a
lot of fuss over your entire claim. If I
talk about ICC Loba Livet plan, then you will get an
inbuilt single private room there,
take an add-on. If you want to reduce the premium of any room category, then
you can also reduce your premium by taking twin sharing room,
but in this build you will get a single
private AC room, whereas in ADA Sir
Go Optima Secure, you will not get any limit,
any capping on room rent.
You can take ROM of any category,
but in maximum hospitals, all the
insurance companies have a
tie-up only for single private AC room, an
MoU is signed. There is no
capping or any kind of sub-limit on ICU and ICCU in both the policies.
Modern treatment,
robotic surgeries, there is no
capping or any sub-limit in both the policies.  Time
limit will be covered. There is no co-payment either.
In both the policies, the
expenses before going to the hospital and after coming back from the hospital,
which is called pre and
post hospitalization, will be covered in IC Lombard's
Elevate plan for 90 days before
and 180 days after, in
comparison, in ADFC Ergo, expenses for 60 days before
and 180 days after will be
covered, which is a very important
feature. E-Consultation: Unlimited
teleconsultation is available in IC Lombard Elevate plan,
but in ADFC Ergo,
you will get this facility only for critical illness.
Day care treatment
is covered up to time limit in both the policies.
Restoration: Unlimited restoration is
for same person same illness in Elevate plan,
but in same person same illness, you will have to make a
gap of 40 days, whereas
in ADFC Ergo, same person same illness will be available,
but there is no gap.  There is no need to do this.
Next day also, if you
go for a claim, you will get a restoration claim for the same person, same illness.
Ambulance: There is
no capping of any kind on road ambulance in both the policies.
If we talk about air ambulance, then
it is an add-on feature in ICC Lombard.
If you need it, then you can add it and
pay its premium. But in ADFC A Go,
you will get the facility of air ambulance in-built,
whose sub-limit will be ₹
lakh per
hospitalization. No claim bonus, which we
call as inbuilt bonus. If we
talk about it, then in Lombard's Elevate plan, the maximum benefit of
20 per time limit will go up to 100%
but it will not be reduced in case of a claim.
Power Booster is an add-on feature in it.
But if we talk about ADFC A Go's Optima
Secure plan, then there is a plus benefit. The maximum benefit will
increase by 50 per time limit every year and will go up
to 100. It will be available even if there is a claim
and even if there is no claim.
Home care will be available.  Dometic treatment is going to be
covered up to sum shed in both the plans.
Annual health checkup is also
given as an add-on in ICC Lord's Elevate plan. If you feel
that you need it, then add it,
otherwise you
can get premium discount by reducing it. But in ADFC R Go
's Optima Secure, it is in-built
for ₹5000000, that is, ₹5000000. The
maximum limit is going to be ₹1.
Alternative treatment, which we
also call AYUSH treatment, is covered.
Up to sum shed is covered in both the policies. Maternity will be an
add-on in Lombard's Elevate plan.
You will get maximum up to ₹1 lakh 10% of
the basic sum shed. But
this facility is not available in ADFC R Go's Optima Secure. If we
talk about consumables, then
you can get consumable cover by taking add-on cover or Lord's Elevate
plan add-on cover,
but in ADFC R Go's Optima
Secure, it is in-built.  You are going to get cover,
wellness program is available in ICC Lombard, that is,
you can take some steps, go to the
gym, do some activity and get a
discount in the premium, but
if I talk about the option of deductible, then this facility is
not available in Lombard's Elevate plan,
but in ADFC Ergo's Optima Secure
plan, you can
reduce the premium by taking a deductible of up to ₹2500000.
So these were two Revolution
Health Insurance plans whose brand image is
very good, whose fundamentals are very
strong and both the insurance
companies are very good companies in themselves, they are
companies with very good brand image, the
products of both are the best selling, as of
today, let's talk a little about the
premium, leaving aside ₹1 lakh, if
I have calculated the premium for the same family size of two adults in Delhi NCR for both the insurance companies, then it will be ₹2491 in
ICC Lombard's Elevate plan and
₹36900 in ADFC Ergo, whereas
if I talk about unlimited time
covered in ICC  Lombard's
Elevate plan will cost ₹1 but
SDFC Ltd will charge a premium of ₹
5227 per lakh. Both the companies are good,
both the plans are good. Talking about the premium,
IC Lombard will be a little economical as compared
to SDFC Ltd but there are a
lot of add-on features there. You can add the add-on features as per your requirement, that is, if
you
need this add-on then add it and do not
add the one which you do not need.
So look at your needs, look at your budget,
after that you decide which of these two
health insurance plans
suits you but my sincere
advice to you is that both the companies are very
good companies. Fox, how did you like
this video? Whatever questions or queries you have related to this video,
you
can ask me in the comment box.
Jai and Jai Bharat for all of you.